Guide to the Remillard Brick Company Records, 1879-1921
Department of Special Collections
Remillard Brick Company Records,
1879-1921
Special Collections M0321
Remillard Brick Company
5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of John E. Polk, 1980
Scope and Content
Title papers, together with various bound ledgers of the Remillard Brick Company (San Francisco and Oakland, California) covering the period 1879 to 1921. Records of sales, purchases, jobs, inventory, employee records, etc.
Container List
- Abstract of title to portions of plot #5, Rancho El Valle de San Jose, Township of Murray, County of Alameda, State of California. Provenance via [Don] A[ntonio] Sunol and the Messrs Bernales. (Box 1)
- Abstract of title to portion of block #5, City of Oakland, County of Alameda, State of California. Provenance via Rancho San Antonio and Domingo and Vincente Peralta. (Box 2)
- Abstract of title to portions of block #21, City of Oakland, County of Alameda, State of California. Inserted is a manuscript map on printed document of Alameda County Surveyor's Office. Provenance of land includes the Rancho San Antonio. (Box 3)
- Ledger 1879-1880 (Box 4)
- Villemain account ledger 1879-1881 (Box 5)
- Accounts Ledger 1881-1883 (Box 6)
- Accounts Ledger 1885 (Box 7)
- Accounts Ledger 1885 (Box 8)
- Accounts Ledger 1888-1889 (Box 9)
- Accounts Ledger 1890 (Box 10)
- Accounts Ledger 1890-1891 (Box 11)
- Accounts Ledger 1890-1891 (Box 12)
- Accounts Ledger 1891 (Box 13)
- Credit Slips 1892-1908 (Box 14)
- Accounts Ledger 1892-1894 (Box 15)
- Accounts Ledger 1897-1898 (Box 16)
- Accounts Ledger 1898-1900 (Box 17)
- Accounts Ledger 1902-1904 (Box 18)
- Accounts Ledger 1902-1904 (Box 19)
- Accounts Ledger 1905-1909 (Box 20)
- Inventory 1904-1909 (Box 21)
- Accounts Register 1907-1909 (Box 22)
- Accounts Register 1910-1913 (Box 23)
- Accounts Register 1887 (Box 24)
- Inventory 1894-1907 (Box 25)
- Employee Records 1904-1910 (Box 26)
- Le salon francais, cash accounts 1917-1920 (Box 27)
- Le salon francais, cash accounts 1921 (Box 28)
- Miscellaneous unbound deeds, title searches, title certificates, tax records, etc. (Box 29)